Finding Aid for The Frick Collection Central Files, 1932-1936 TFC.0400.010
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
- Central Files, 1935
  - Planting - Olmsted Brothers [2 folders], 1935 (Box 29, Folder 10-11)
    Re Garden Court planting and planting near main entrance on 70th Street. Photograph transferred to The Frick Collection - Photographs; folder contains photocopy of photograph.
  - Planting - Pope, John Russell, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] [11 folders], 1935 (Box 29, Folder 13-23)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Bids for Subcontract Work, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Bills, Correspondence, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Drawings and Samples Submitted [4 folders], 1935 (Box 30, Folder 1-4)
    Contains forms noting the transmission of architectural drawings delivered to The Frick Collection.
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Fees, 1935-1936 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Minutes of Weekly Conferences [4 folders], 1935 (Box 30, Folder 6-9)
    Re items approved and authorized, discussed, or pending action.
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Orders, 1935 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Payments on Order, 1933-1937 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Pope, John Russell [architect] - Supplements Showing Changes to Plans, 1934-1935 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Post Cards, 1935 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    Contains mock-up samples with suggested changes. Printed by the Meriden Gravure Company.
  - Printing, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Contains samples of Collection printed materials (mailings, forms, invitations), as well as samples from vendors.
  - Progress, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Projection Equipment - Commercial Radio - Sound Corp., 1935 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    Installed RCA photophone and sound equipment in Lecture Room.
  - Projection Equipment - Continental Theatre Accessories, Inc., 1933-1934 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Projection Equipment - Film Storage, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Projection Equipment - Miscellaneous, 1933-1935 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    Includes estimates from various companies and discussion of types of equipment required.
  - Projection Equipment - National Theatre Supply Co., 1935 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Protection - General, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Publicity, 1932-1935 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - P - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    Scope and Content Note
    Park Association of N.Y. City
    Plummer, Wm. H. & Co. Ltd. - Re vases.
    Plumbing
    Police, Special - Re appointment of four members of The Frick Collection security staff as special patrolmen.
  - Remington Rand Inc., 1935-1936 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    Re typewriters and related supplies.
  - Repairs - Building [2 folders], 1935-1936 (Box 31, Folder 12-13)
    Contains authorizations for payment and invoices from subcontractors forwarded by Marc Eidlitz & Son.
  - Report of Organizing Director to Trustees, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    Contains summary report covering March 5 to December 31, 1935. Includes sections on the progress of operations, condition of objects stored in vault, inventory checks, estimated final costs, construction account expenses, general repairs, insurance, contracts, tax exemption, rules and regulations, catalogues and post cards, official opening, circulation, admission, attendance, Holmes electric protection, and financial statements.
  - Requests for Admission, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    Correspondents include Royal Cortissoz and Count Sforza.
  - Requests for Admission - Groups, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Requests for Catalogue, 1933-1935 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Requests for General Information, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Requests for Information re The Frick Collection, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Requests for Permission to Reproduce Pictures, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Requests for Photographs, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. [Trustee], 1935 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Roofing and Repairs, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Rules and Regulations, 1932-1935 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    Contains draft copies and printed version, and samples from other museums.
  - R - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    Reed Engineering Co.
    Rooms - Schedule of Rooms and Spaces in the Collection (numbers assigned to each space correspond to those used on blueprints).
  - Salaries and Wages - Schedule, 1932-1935 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Salvage, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Samples [2 folders], 1935 (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
    Contains fabric samples of gimp, the organ curtain, bulletin board linings, velvet rope covers, coat room equipment finish, ventilighters, and the velvet lining of enamel cases.
  - Seating for Lecture Hall [Lecture Room], 1935 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    Contains photographs of chairs, including one with a hand-drawn stenciled design overlay, correspondence with vendors, and company literature.
  - Services, etc., 1935 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    Re Seamstresses, caterer, and floor maintenance.
  - Shutter for Window - Miss Frick's Office, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Sidewalks, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Soundproofing, 1933-1935 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - South Hall Changes, 1933-1935 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    Re removing and replacing marble, installing a new picture outlet, and replacing vacuum outlet.
  - Standards, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    Re bronze posts that support velvet guide ropes in the Collection.
  - Standpipe - Stair A, 1934-1935 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Statements - Budget, 1932-1935 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Statements - Construction Account, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Statements - Construction Account - U.S. Trust Company, 1935-1936 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Statements - Construction Connected Items, 1934-1935 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Statements - Frick Collection House Account, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Statements - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Syska & Hennessy [consulting engineer], 1935 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Syska & Hennessy [consulting engineer] - Bills, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Syska & Hennessy [consulting engineer] - Copies of Letters, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Syska & Hennessy [consulting engineer] - Fees, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - S - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    Sachs, Prof. Paul J. [Harvard University]
    Schmidt, Carl F. - Contains note to see "Schmidt, Carl F." file in 1974 Central Files re work he did for the Hayden Company on The Frick Collection interiors.
    Senn-Herrick Corporation - Re reinforced concrete construction.
    Sherwin, Harold B.
    Simon Ventilighter Co. Inc.
    Sizer, Theodore
    Steuben Glass, Inc.
    Stonework - Pointing
    Storage (Hayes)
    Suburban Bronze Works
    Sterner, Mr. [Fogg Art Museum]
  - Tax Exemption - Sales Tax, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Tax Exemption Proceedings (Property), 1935 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Taxes, Income [RESTRICTED FILE], 1935 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Telephone System - Collection - Miscellaneous, 1933-1935 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Telephone System - Collection - New York Telephone, 1933-1935 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Telephone System - Library, 1933-1935 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Thermopane Glass, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Ticket Office, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Trustees - Materials for Meetings, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Trustees - Minutes of Meetings [RESTRICTED FILE], 1935 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Turnstiles, 1934-1935 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    Re turnstile installed in Reception Hall to record attendance.
  - T - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    Tiles
    Travel
    Typing - Re Manuscript Typing Service.
  - United States Trust Company, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Vacation Schedules, 1932-1937 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Vacuum Cleaning, 1933-1935 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Vault, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - V - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    Vases
    Venetian Blinds
    Vezin, Charles
  - Wall of Building "B" - Rear, 1934-1935 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Western Union, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    Contains text of telegrams sent.
  - W - Miscellaneous, 1934-1935 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    Water
    Watson, Thomas E.
    Weather Bureau
    Wheel Chairs
    Windows
    Wittenmeier Machinery Co. - Re Freon gas.
    Worcester Museum of Art
  - X-Y-Z - Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 21)
- Central Files, 1936
  - Accounts, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Accounts - Balance Unexpended, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Accounts - Reimbursements, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Admission Cards - Special, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    Re special admission cards for Trustees.
  - Admission Tickets, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Aeolian-Skinner Organ Company, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Air Conditioning - Dust, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    Re accumulation of dust in the Frick Art Reference Library book stacks.
  - Air Conditioning - Marc Eidlitz & Son, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Air Conditioning - Miscellaneous, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    Oversize blueprint drawing stored in Box C.
  - Air Conditioning - John Russell Pope, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Air Conditioning - Syska & Hennessy, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - American Association of Museums, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - American District Telegraph Company, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Applications for Employment [RESTRICTED FILE], 1932-1936 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Applications - Maintenance [RESTRICTED FILE], 1936 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Art Exhibitions, etc., 1936 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Attendance Reports, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    Contains weekly reports of number of visitors (by the hour), and annual report. "The 100,000 visitor passed through the turnstile Saturday afternoon, June 27, 1936."
  - A - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    Albright Art Gallery
    Almirall & Company, Inc.
    Anderson, Charles G.
    Art Congress
  - Baker, George F. [Trustee], 1936 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Bludworth, Inc., 1936 (Box 34, Folder 22)
    Service contractor for organ and sound film projection system for Lecture Room.
  - Books, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Books for Sale, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - By-Laws, 1937 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - B - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 26)
    Bank for Savings
    Bradley, William & Son - Re cut stone and marble.
    Brinks, Inc.
    Brooklyn Museum
    Browning Brothers - Re heavy hardware.
  - Cabinet Work, 1934-1936 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    Contains correspondence with Hayden Co. Includes formula used to clean walnut in Oval Room.
  - Cabinet Work - Benches, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    Re walnut benches in East Gallery, West Gallery, and Oval Room.
  - Cable Address, etc., 1936 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Cafeteria, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Catalogue, Large - Hildreth, E. L. & Co., 1936 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Catalogue Sales Department, 1935-1936 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    Contains profit and loss statements, discussion of sales display, and statistics. Sales concerns catalogues, check lists, post cards, and photographs.
  - Catalogue Sales Department - Inventory - Accumulative, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Catalogue Sales Department - Inventory - Catalogues, Check Lists and Post Cards [2 folders], 1936 (Box 35, Folder 8-9)
  - Catalogue Sales Department - Inventory - Photographs, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Catalogue Sales Department - Inventory - Post Cards, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Catalogue Sales Department - Inventory - Receipts [3 folders], 1936-1937 (Box 35, Folder 12-14)
  - Catalogues and Check Lists - Hildreth, E. L. & Co., 1936 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    Re printing of catalogues and check lists.
  - Catalogues, Check Lists, Post Cards, Etc. - Distribution of Certificates, 1935-1936 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Certificates, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    Contains Certificates of Electrical Inspection.
  - Clippings - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - College Art Association, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Comments on Collection, 1935-1936 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    Contains summary of overheard comments made by patrons.
  - Committee, Executive, 1936 Jan.-Feb. (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Committee, Executive [5 folders], 1936 Mar.-Dec. (Box 36, Folder 1-5)
  - Committee, Executive - Material for Meetings, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Committee, Executive - Minutes of Meetings, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Complaints, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Construction Account, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Construction Account - Bills Paid, 1935-1936 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Construction - Special Items Paid by Frick Art Reference Library, 1934-1936 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    Special items include wood grilles, antique glazing, clock dials, lunch room countertop, finishes of thermostats, switch plates, and bathroom fixtures.
  - Court - Lighting for Plants, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    Re sodium vapor irradiator lamps for use at night. General Electric Vapor Lamp Company.
  - Customs, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - C - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    Card Indices Room [Frick Art Reference Library]
    Carnegie Corporation of New York
    Carnegie Institute
    Cleveland Museum of Art
    Courtauld Institute of Art
    Congrès International d'Histoire de l'Art
  - Decorating, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    Contains list of wall coverings, including the fabric type and supplier.
  - D - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    Dun & Bradstreet, Inc. - Contains business card only.
    Dwight, H.G. [Assistant Director of The Frick Collection]
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors], 1936 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    Contains February 5, 1936 thank you letter from Frederick Mortimer Clapp to Mr. P.S. Vermilya of Marc Eidlitz & Sons. Also mentioned is modification to velvet on west wall of the East Gallery by Hayden Company.
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors] - Bills and Requisitions, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors] - Bills re Maintenance, 1935-1936 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors] - Copies of Letters, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors] - Costs, Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors] - Fees, 1935-1936 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors] - Statements of Estimated Cost Status, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors] - Statements of Estimated Cost Status - Frederick Mortimer Clapp Analysis of, 1934-1937 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    Includes statements of extra costs.
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors] - Statements of Estimated Cost Status - Frederick Mortimer Clapp Analysis of - Work Sheets [2 folders], 1933-1936 (Box 36, Folder 25-26)
  - Eidlitz, Marc & Son [general contractors] - Statements of Expenditures and Commitments, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    Oversize statements stored in Box B.
  - Employees [RESTRICTED FILE], 1936 (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - Employees - Attendance [RESTRICTED FILE], 1935-1936 (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - Equipment and Supplies - Office, 1935-1936 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Equipment and Supplies for Sale, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - E - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    Education - Contains pamphlets from Brooklyn Museum and the Gallery School of Art.
  - Fifth Avenue Association, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Fire Protection, 1935-1936 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    Re Staff Smoking Room.
  - Flood - Bowling Alley, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Flood Control, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Flowers, 1935-1936 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    Re plants around the Garden Court Fountain and cut flowers for The Frick Collection galleries for the opening.
  - Fogg Art Museum, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Frick, Childs [Trustee], 1936 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    Contains list of salvage items he received in March, and a June 25, 1936 letter re the rehanging of the East Gallery and the West Gallery.
  - Frick, Miss Helen C. [Trustee], 1935-1936 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    Contains list of books found in The Frick Collection Library, but not listed in 1920 inventory, and a May 8, 1936 list of furniture and decorative items shipped to Pride's Crossing. Also includes correspondence re complaints about Miss Frick's private elevator in the Library, Clapp's thoughts on his role in the work done to The Frick Collection, and a Frick Collection catalogue raisonné. Also contains a letter from Clapp to Miss Frick thanking her for the article on telepathy and describing his attendance at "the exercises at the Roosevelt Memorial."
  - Frick Art Reference Library, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    Contains information on the clock at bottom of The Frick Collection main staircase, and the Library flagpoles.
  - Frick Art Reference Library - Cafeteria Ceiling, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Frick Art Reference Library - Elevators, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    Re breakdowns of Helen Clay Frick's private elevator in the Library.
  - Frick Art Reference Library - Furniture, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    Re Reading Room chairs.
  - Frick Art Reference Library - Manning, Ethelwyn [Librarian], 1936 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Frick Art Reference Library - Lunette, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    Contains Marc Eidlitz & Son estimate for changes to the lunette above the Library entrance.
  - Frick Art Reference Library - Servicing, 1936-1937 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Frick Art Reference Library - Servicing - Costs, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Frick Art Reference Library - Servicing - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Frick Art Reference Library - Utilities Bills, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Furniture and Furnishings - Office [2 folders], 1935-1936 (Box 37, Folder 22-23)
    Includes vendor brochures, and some mention of Collection furniture in public areas.
  - Furniture and Furnishings - Office - Desk Lamps, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - F - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Gardner Museum - Boston [Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum], 1936 (Box 37, Folder 26)
    Contains correspondence with Director Morris Carter.
  - Griggs, Maitland F. [Trustee], 1936 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Guaranty Trust Company of New York - Statements [2 folders], 1936 (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
  - G - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Greene, Belle da Costa - Contains business card only.
    Goldman, Henry
  - Hammond, John Henry [The Frick Collection Counsel], 1936 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Re April 28, 1936 changes to The Frick Collection admission: Monday is ticketless; Tuesday-Friday 10:00 a.m. to 1:00 p.m. are ticketless; and hours extended to 5:00 p.m. Also includes an interpretation of Henry Clay Frick's will regarding whether the removal of art objects and furnishings from the building is allowed for cleaning purposes.
  - Havemeyer, Horace [Trustee], 1936 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Holmes Electric Protection, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - H - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    Hale, Cushman & Flint
    Hardware
    Hildreth, E. L. & Company
    Huntington Library and Art Gallery
  - Insurance - General, undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Insurance and Pension Data [RESTRICTED FILE], 1935-1936 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Inventory, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    Contains list of articles in third floor cedar closet, and Registrar forms and cards used for items in The Frick Collection.
  - Inventory - Data from Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    Contains forms and samples detailing their registrar's system.
  - Inventory - Data from Brooklyn Museum, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Inventory - Data from Cincinnati Art Museum, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Inventory - Data from City Art Museum, St. Louis, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Inventory - Data from Pennsylvania Museum of Art, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Inventory - Data from William Rockhill Nelson Gallery, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Inventory - Data from Toledo Museum of Art, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Inventory - Furniture Stored for Mrs. Childs Frick (Mr. Naughton's Records), 1934-1936 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Inventory - House Cleaning (Mr. Naughton's Notes), 1936 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Inventory - Photographer's Equipment (Mr. Naughton's Records), 1936-1937 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Inventory - Property of Miss Frick Removed from Building, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    Contains nine lists of Helen Clay Frick's items removed from One East 70th Street, organized by where they were shipped, and a description of how Miss Frick's personal property was packed and removed from the building, from 1931-1936.
  - Invitations, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Keys, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Knoedler, M. & Company, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - K - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    Kress, S. H. & Co.
  - Labels - E. L. Hildreth & Co., 1936 (Box 38, Folder 27)
    Printer of labels for works of art and Collection signage. Contains paper samples and proofs. Oversize galley proofs stored in Box B.
  - Labels - Rowland, Stanley J., 1936 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    Re labels for sculpture and Piero della Francesca.
  - Lighting, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Lighting - Galleries, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    Re lighting in Fragonard Room and Boucher Room.
  - Lost and Found Articles, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - L - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    Lithographs - Re Odilon Redon.
  - Mailing List, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    Re mailing list for organ recitals.
  - Mailing List - Lecture Schedule, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Maintenance and Operating Account, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Maintenance Equipment, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Maintenance of Equipment, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Maintenance of Equipment - Permits, Licenses, etc., 1935-1936 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Mellon, Andrew W. [Trustee], 1936 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Memoranda, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Memoranda - F.M. Clapp [Director], 1936 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    Re miscellaneous subjects, including copyrighting of Frick Collection photographs, a possible concert program, and lists of items to take up with the Executive Committee. Note that the museum will be closed in August for cleaning, rehanging of some paintings "in order to facilitate their inspection by larger numbers," installation of a new seating arrangement in the Lecture Room and modification of lighting. Summaries of meetings with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (October 23, 1936 memo details 51 different items discussed) and telephone conversations with Helen Clay Frick. June 25, 1936 memo notes: "No tickets are required now except at moments of great influx of visitors beyond the capacity of the galleries as on some few Saturday afternoons but generally speaking no further tickets are required."
  - Memoranda - Docents, 1935 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Memoranda - Mr. Dwight [Assistant Director], 1936 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Memoranda - Mr. Watson [Superintendent], 1936 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    Contains Superintendent's memos regarding building maintenance and operation.
  - Memoranda - Galchus, John [Stock keeper], 1936 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Memoranda - Mr. Matthew [Clerk of the Works], 1936 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Memoranda - Mr. Naughton [Assistant to Director], 1936 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    Contains memo from Clapp outlining Mr. Naughton's duties, in addition to general assistance to the Director and Assistant Director.
  - Memoranda - Mr. Whitmore (J.E.) [Captain of Guards], 1936 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Metropolitan Museum, 1926, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 20)
    Contains lecture program, booklet of instructions to attendants (1926), and invitation to Eighth Annual Pistol Competition between the Attendants and the Night Guards of the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
  - Mimeographing, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 21)